<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<entry><title>Data/Python Team leader</title><link href="https://www.afpy.org/jobs/data-python-team-leader" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-14T17:24:06+01:00</published><updated>2016-01-14T17:24:08+01:00</updated><author><name>kpler</name><email>jobs@kpler.com</email></author><id>https://www.afpy.org/jobs/data-python-team-leader</id><summary type="html">We design B2B services on real-time data for commodity traders. 

We aggregate data from hundreds of sources, ranging from satellite data to governmental and shipping databases, and run algorithms on top of it to predict the flows of energy. Dataviz with maps and charts make the information actionable.


Position

Kpler is looking for a Data / Python team leader, technical expert on Python  and more generally on the treatment of flows data.

Within our engineering team of developers, you will participate in the development and improvement of our data processing features from coding and testing to deployment and support)  on large volumes of complex data.



Responsibilities

Design and implement complex data integration and processing features
Guide work of junior developers
Participate in architectural evolutions of the system
Contribute to improvement of processes  and technology watch

For example, you will improve our vessels destination forecast algorithm or on ways determine stakeholders in complex business transactions.


Requirements

Expert : Python / Object-oriented programming
Strong knowledge : SQL (PostgreSQL)
Good level : ORM (SQLAlchemy)
Basic : Scripting sur Linux (Bash)
Pluses : Play2 Scala, ElasticSearch, AWS, Heroku
Graduated from an IT degree, with at least 4 years of experience 
Ideally with a first experience in start up
There is 9 different nationalities at Kpler, you must be able to interact with all team members in a functional English
Personal qualities : 
Crafty, handy and pragmatic, you commit on Open source projects and you are present on GitHub
Open-minded, you are ready to understand our specific business issues

Other


Location : Paris, Beaubourg - 4ème arrondissement
Start date : Asap
Salary : According to profile and experience
Nature of contract: CDI / Full-time
</summary><content type="html"></content><company>Kpler</company><address>4 rue de jarente</address><contact>Laurine Pohl</contact><location></location><phone>0183818790</phone></entry>