<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<entry><title>Data/Python Developer</title><link href="https://www.afpy.org/jobs/data-python-developer" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-10T12:47:01+02:00</published><updated>2016-08-10T13:18:17+02:00</updated><author><name>kpler</name><email>jobs@kpler.com</email></author><id>https://www.afpy.org/jobs/data-python-developer</id><summary type="html">You will participate in the evolution of our platform app.kpler.com (code, test, deployment, support) and derived applications with the aim of extracting (API, scraping), consolidating, (ETL), and applying algorithms (data-mining, business rules) on large data sets, and make them available (Postgres, ElasticSearch).
​
For example, you will improve our vessel destination forecast algorithm.
​
You will be tested on, and expected  to work with the following stack :
​
Python,  Posgresql, SQLAlchemy, ElasticSearch, AWS...
​
The technical team works in lean mode to continually improve our SaaS applications and API.

</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;- IT or Engineer recently graduated, you have already worked on projects around data processing (ETL, data streaming, data mining ...) in Python and ideally with a first experience in startups&lt;br /&gt;- Knowledge in Scala could be a plus&lt;br /&gt;- Crafty, handy and pragmatic, you code on Linux / Mac and are both comfortable with CLI and graphical interfaces&lt;br /&gt;- You commit on Open source projects and you are present on GitHub&lt;br /&gt;- There is more than 12 different nationalities at Kpler, you must be able to interact with all team members in a functional English&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Kpler&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in Paris in 2009, Kpler is an intelligence company providing transparency solutions in energy markets. We develop proprietary technologies that systematically&lt;strong&gt; aggregate data from hundreds of sources&lt;/strong&gt;, ranging from logistics and commercial, to governmental and shipping databases. By connecting the dots across fragmented information landscapes, we are able to deliver our clients with unique real-time market coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We rely on intelligent people to build intelligent software. Our team is composed of individuals of various backgrounds, with diversified skill sets and international experiences. Our clients are players across the energy market spectrum, with offices from Houston to Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;</content><company>Kpler</company><address>4 rue de jarente</address><contact>Cécile Pichon</contact><location></location><phone></phone><link href="http://www.kpler.com/" rel="about"></link><link href="http://careers.kpler.com/jobs/data-python-developer_paris_KPLER_yV1k4qO" rel="via"></link></entry>