<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<entry><title>Développeur Python</title><link href="https://www.afpy.org/jobs/developpeur-python-4" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-11-04T15:18:54+01:00</published><updated>2013-11-04T15:56:23+01:00</updated><author><name>vaurientis</name><email>vaurientis@sii.fi</email></author><id>https://www.afpy.org/jobs/developpeur-python-4</id><summary type="html">Le groupe SII est au cœur de l’économie de l’innovation avec 4500 consultants et une présence internationale sur 45 sites. Pour ses collaborateurs SII c’est aussi de la convivialité, de la technicité et des métiers passionnants qui génèrent expériences et opportunités de carrières. 

 Nos activités d’ingénierie et de conseil fédèrent des métiers multiples et une large diversité d’expertises. Ensemble, nous accompagnons la compétitivité et la performance des produits de nos clients dans des secteurs aussi variés que le spatial, l’aéronautique, les télécoms, l’électronique, la défense, l’automobile, l’énergie, la finance ou la distribution. 

 Nous recherchons pour le compte de notre client, multinationale de renom basée à Montpellier, un développeur Python.
 
 Being part of the Quality Assurance team, you will be in charge of :

 o ensuring, with the whole team, that the releases of the software product are as expected (meeting Quality Release Criteria)

 o writing and/or reviewing the automated test plans according to the requirements, implementing and validating them

 o checking and following-up the results on the continuous integration system. 

 o enhancing the automation tools/scripts required to implement these tests and report result. 


 The mission will consist in:

 - Python scripting, exercising existing API for Performance Benchmark testing

 - Enhancing the homegrown automation framework to run the test 

 - Tailoring the Sikuli GUI based testing framework using Python to meet the manual tester’s needs

 You will work in an international environnement, you need to have a good level in English.

 Démarrage immédiat
</summary><content type="html"></content><company>SII</company><address></address><contact>Vanessa AURIENTIS</contact><location></location><phone>06 20 26 03 34</phone><link href="http://www.groupe-sii.com/fr" rel="about"></link></entry>