<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<entry><title>Développeur Python pour l'analyse du climat</title><link href="https://www.afpy.org/jobs/developpeur-python-pour-lanalyse-du-climat" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-07T14:53:10+02:00</published><updated>2015-02-23T12:45:24+01:00</updated><author><name>senesi</name><email>senesi@meteo.fr</email></author><id>https://www.afpy.org/jobs/developpeur-python-pour-lanalyse-du-climat</id><summary type="html">Ingénieur en développement d'un environnemrnt pour l'analyse des simulationsclimatiques</summary><content type="html">&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location and duration&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;: Toulouse, France. 18 months, renewable for 14 months.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target start date&lt;/strong&gt; : 1st February 2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Net Salary&lt;/strong&gt; : 1900 to 2200 € /month (depending on experience – ruled by CNRS guidelines)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Qualification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; Engineer or PhD degree in computer science or applied mathematics; a similar qualification in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;E&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;arth &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;S&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;cience&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; can also be considered&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working language&lt;/strong&gt; : french ; required fluency in reading/writing English and good skills in speaking/listening&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;: python, climate diagnostics suite, NetCDF, WPS, ESGF, parallel distributed processing, symbolic rewriting, advanced GUI for scientific data browsing, Open Source development tools&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt; : &lt;a class="western" href="mailto:Stephane.Senesi@meteo.fr"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Stephane.Senesi@meteo.fr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;: please send a C.V. by e-mail &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;before &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; Nov, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;together with contact&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; information (affiliation, position and e-mail) of one or two referees who could recommend your application&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Context&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;: &lt;a class="western" href="http://www.cnrm-game-meteo.fr/spip.php?rubrique1&amp;amp;lang=en"&gt;CNRM – GAME&lt;/a&gt; (Centre National de Recherches Météorologiques – &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;UMR 3589&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;) is a leading research center in climate and climate change.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; In the context of the french ANR project CONVERGENCE, and in close cooperation with IPSL (Institut Pierre Simon Laplace),  &lt;strong&gt;CNRM-GAME&lt;/strong&gt; develops &lt;strong&gt;CliMAF&lt;/strong&gt;, a Climate Model Assessment Framework. The aim of CliMAF is to make a breakthrough progress with the environment offered to climate scientists for the monitoring of climate simulation and the analysis of their results. This involves providing them with easy to use basic analysis operations, and convenient ways to add any basic or advanced operation, and compose them in analysis workflows releasing them of data access and move issues ensuring easy access to the worldwide climate datasets on the ESGF, and to the in-house datasets&lt;br /&gt;using efficiently distributed processing resources, both at local scale using proprietary protocols and at the worldwide scale using WPS or similar ESFG compute API promoting their collaboration by providing an infrastructure to share diagnostic tools and more generally, allowing them to focus on the science of the analyses to perform&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workplan and profile for the position&lt;/strong&gt; :  Depending on the experience of the candidate, the work may focus on various parts of the framework development :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;symbolic handling and rewriting of workflows, and user interface to workflow representations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;interfacing with upcoming Web Processing Service or other Compute capabilities on the Earth System Grid Federation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;smart caching of workflow results, indexed using symbolic workflow representations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;graphical user interface for i) elaborating the specification of workflows, ii) presentation of analysis results, and iii) configuration of the workflows environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;workflow distributed execution planning w.r.t. available ressources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developing dedicated climate analysis operators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sharing climate analysis operators semantics and their documentation among scientists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We are therefore seeking candidates with a sound experience in Python and object programming, and an experience in some of theses domains : distributed processing (incl. MPI), remote processing (Web Processing Services and batch systems), climate analysis tools (NetCDF,  OpenDAP, CDAT, CDO, NCO, OCGIS ...), graphical user interface development tools, Open Source development tools. Some practice with Mongo DB would be appreciated, too. &lt;/p&gt;</content><company>Météo-France - CNRM</company><address>CNRM-GMGEC
42 av Coriolis
31000 TOULOUSE CEDEX</address><contact>Stephane Sénési</contact><location></location><phone></phone><link href="http://www.cnrm-game-meteo.fr" rel="about"></link></entry>