<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<entry><title>Technical Lead / Python-MongoDB-AJAX - Paris</title><link href="https://www.afpy.org/jobs/lodog-zenlist" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-06-21T15:17:35+02:00</published><updated>2013-03-31T22:50:20+02:00</updated><author><name>admin</name><email>lkalisky@gmail.com</email></author><id>https://www.afpy.org/jobs/lodog-zenlist</id><summary type="html">We are looking for a talented, energetic and proactive senior developer: Someone who can jump into an existing project with an existing architecture, and lead us though a high-pressure growth stage. This is an excellent opportunity for someone who wants to get into a promising startup early, and help us innovate and disrupt a multi-billion-dollar global industry.</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Zenlist: Classifieds for Every Website&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zenlist is based on a simple idea: Let visitors to any website connect and transact via classified ads. In the process, we&amp;#8217;re making online classifieds more social and giving website publishers a new way to generate revenue. Think &amp;#8220;Craigslist meets Google ads&amp;#8221;. To this end, we&amp;#8217;ve created the first embeddable classified listings system that also includes a managed content network. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We previously raised a small seed round from Paris- and San Francisco-based angel investors. Today we have a functional minimum viable product in private beta release. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="TheOpportunity"&gt;The Opportunity&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a talented, energetic and proactive senior developer: Someone who can jump into an existing project with an existing architecture, and lead us though a high-pressure growth stage. This is an excellent opportunity for someone who wants to get into a promising startup early, and help us innovate and disrupt a multi-billion-dollar global industry. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="Requirements"&gt;Requirements &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should be ninja-level in:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Python / Turbogears&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;MongoDB&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;jQuery &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hand-tooled JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;xHTML, CSS&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, the following skills/experience are critical:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unix server administration &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Third-party authentication protocols (Facebook, Twitter, Google, Yahoo!)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;API development&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Development of highly scalable systems&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id="Responsibilities"&gt;Responsibilities&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re looking for more than just a developer. We&amp;#8217;re looking for someone with architectural vision, business savvy, and entrepreneurial energy. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Maintain, streamline, and improve our existing technology platform&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Design and implement new algorithms to power our search and recommendation engines&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Contribute to our R&amp;amp;D of innovative content acquisition and distribution methods&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id="WhatWeCanOffer"&gt;What We Can Offer&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are an early-stage startup with minimal resources, and we are therefore seeking someone who is not afraid to take risks. We offer a basic minimum salary, as well as significant equity in our company. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="Interested"&gt;Interested?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Send your CV and a cover letter to &lt;a href="mailto:lorin@zenlist.com"&gt;lorin@zenlist.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><company>Zenlist</company><address></address><contact>Lorin Kalisky</contact><location></location><phone>06 74 74 88 85</phone><link href="http://zenlist.com" rel="about"></link></entry>