<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<entry><title>Python Software Engineer - Fluendo</title><link href="https://www.afpy.org/jobs/ogrisel-afpyjob.2008-02-06.8634136554" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-02-06T14:01:04+01:00</published><updated>2013-03-31T22:50:32+02:00</updated><author><name>admin</name><email>rrhh@fluendo.com</email></author><id>https://www.afpy.org/jobs/ogrisel-afpyjob.2008-02-06.8634136554</id><summary type="html">
Our streaming media platform is a loosely-coupled cluster system,
designed to deliver tens to hundreds of gigabits per second to clients
across the globe. It is written mostly in Python (using Twisted), and
runs on Linux servers. The core streaming software, Flumotion, is an
open-source project, available at http://www.flumotion.net/, whilst
the advanced clustering software is proprietary.

Fluendo is looking for a developer to join their team of streaming
server developers and expand the video-on-demand functionality of
Flumotion. Tasks include integrating new functionality in the
streaming server core, adding functionality to clustering software,
and providing a web-based frontend for managing and transcoding
customers' VOD files.</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="company-profile"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name="company-profile"&gt;Company Profile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our group is a multimedia product and services provider. Our
innovation has positioned us as one of the leading companies in audio
and video streaming via internet and mobile networks. Due to our
growth, we are looking for an experienced Software Engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will have the opportunity to join a unique fast growing technology
company with a very high skill, experienced team working with Open
Source technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="position-requirements-skills-characteristics"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name="position-requirements-skills-characteristics"&gt;Position Requirements (skills, characteristics)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with software development in one or more of: multimedia
systems, Linux/UNIX, Python, Twisted, Web services, distributed
systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fluency (both written and spoken) in English is required (this is
the main operating language of the company). Working knowledge of
Spanish is strongly desired, but excellent candidates without this
will be considered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to learn new programming languages and libraries rapidly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must work well with the rest of the our team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 or more years of development experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge of Python or similar dynamic languages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="position-special-skills-for-identifying-top-candidates"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name="position-special-skills-for-identifying-top-candidates"&gt;Position Special Skills (for identifying TOP candidates)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with open source development models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with multimedia frameworks (e.g. GStreamer, DirectShow).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience developing with Twisted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proven ability to diagnose and debug complex multi-level problems in
large-scale software systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><company>Fluendo</company><address></address><contact>Cristina Cohí (HR Assistant)</contact><location></location><phone></phone><link href="http://www.flumotion.com" rel="via"></link></entry>