<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<entry><title>OpenERP Developer / Suisse</title><link href="https://www.afpy.org/jobs/openerp-developer-suisse" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-01-15T10:38:08+01:00</published><updated>2014-01-19T22:08:14+01:00</updated><author><name>florentx</name><email>florent.xicluna@wingo.ch</email></author><id>https://www.afpy.org/jobs/openerp-developer-suisse</id><summary type="html">Swisscom supplies the optical fibres, our young subsidiary WinGo provides the Internet, the telephony and the digital TV. Do you want to contribute your know-how in a small, flexible team?</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="http://direktlink.prospective.ch/?view=9F5746EF-EA3B-EF8E-F3848BEE94AFA417"&gt;Lien vers l'annonce originale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you show your e-ticket in the train lately, check your bank statement in the tram, or send an e-mail from the coffee shop? Do you save your data in the cloud so you can access it with your apps? Swisscom makes it all possible. And to keep everything running smoothly, we need you here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;That's why we need you:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At WinGo we make very intensive use of our OpenERP system for product management, contract administration, order processing, accounting and the financial processes. You will interact within our very dynamic IT team of engineers and continue to develop the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=" "&gt;Your responsibility:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=" "&gt;We have a start-up mentality which is infectious and we're keen on new ideas: you enhance our OpenERP system by developing new features together with the corresponding teams. You like a technological challenge and will make a contribution to our corporate success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=" "&gt;Your background:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good knowledge of Python, at least 2 years of practical experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database - experience, preferably with PostgreSQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with OpenERP an advantage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preferably experience with Bazaar, Git, HTML, Javascript, SOAP, REST etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideally familiar with B2C or B2B2C business processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have the ability to understand and solve technical problems and you are enthusiastic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge of spoken and written English required, ideally also German or French&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="http://direktlink.prospective.ch/?view=9F5746EF-EA3B-EF8E-F3848BEE94AFA417"&gt;Apply now:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;</content><company>WinGo SA</company><address>1700 Fribourg - Suisse</address><contact>Florent Xicluna</contact><location></location><phone></phone><link href="http://www.wingo.ch/" rel="about"></link><link href="http://direktlink.prospective.ch/?view=9F5746EF-EA3B-EF8E-F3848BEE94AFA417" rel="via"></link></entry>