<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<entry><title>Python Cloud Platform Engineer</title><link href="https://www.afpy.org/jobs/python-cloud-platform-engineer" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-12-09T15:12:02+01:00</published><updated>2014-12-09T15:12:03+01:00</updated><author><name>ddnmeudon</name><email>mfloury@ddn.com</email></author><id>https://www.afpy.org/jobs/python-cloud-platform-engineer</id><summary type="html">DataDirect Networks (DDN.com) is a world leader in massively scalable storage. DDN is opening a new R&amp;D facilities in France, nearby Paris.This lab is focused on emerging technologies and is developing breakthrough products.
DDN is looking for a bright and exceptional senior software engineers to help us build the next generation of Hybrid Cloud solutions, Candidate must be passionate about technology and have strong Python System programming expertise.  Responsibilities include the design and development of various components of the big data platform, such as Installation/Deployment, Administration tooling, cluster monitoring and upgrades. The candidate will design, implement and maintain our Platform Orchestration framework for cluster management and will be part of our platform engineering team.

The ideal candidate will possess a high level of technical creativity, problem solving ability, software process and lifecycle expertise, communication skills, and an ability to work independently as well as part of a team.</summary><content type="html">Responsibilities for this role include but are not limited to:
Design and develop various new components of the big data platform (such as Installation/Deployment, Administration tooling, cluster monitoring and upgrades).
Design, implement and maintain our Platform Orchestration framework for cluster management and will be part of our platform engineering team.
Research and experiment with emerging technologies and tools related to big data
Ability to project lead and work independently within distributed teams.
Help DDN build the next generation of Hybrid Cloud solutions
Clearly documenting all aspects of his work;
Communicate effectively with colleagues;
Effectively manage time on the projects assigned
Providing regular reports on your project progress to other team members and senior management</content><company>DataDirect Network</company><address>10-12 rue Andras Beck,
Meudon la foret</address><contact>Magalie Floury</contact><location></location><phone>+33.1.75.95.10.95</phone><link href="http://www.ddn.com/" rel="about"></link><link href="https://careers-ddn.icims.com/jobs/1528/python-cloud-platform-engineer/job" rel="via"></link></entry>