<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<entry><title>Python Software Engineer</title><link href="https://www.afpy.org/jobs/python-software-engineer-2" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-28T18:29:15+01:00</published><updated>2015-10-28T18:41:58+01:00</updated><author><name>vlandrieux</name><email>v.landrieux@criteo.com</email></author><id>https://www.afpy.org/jobs/python-software-engineer-2</id><summary type="html">CRITEO is looking to recruit engineers who turn it up to eleven for its headquarters in Paris, France.

 

Your mission:

As a Python developer at Criteo you will be working to improve the reliability and performance of our services.

You will work in a team of 4 and work side by side with our Ops, Hosting, Network and developers team to provide the next generation of asset management and provisioning tool.

Through this unique component we want to provide a portal and an API to manage all our servers. 

Offer cutting-edge infrastructure services to internal customers : on-demand resource allocation, automatic configuration, self-registration to service discovery and inventory. Either by developing specifics functionality, or integrating open sources technologies ( puppet, chef, capistrano, nagios, centreon, altiris, cobbler, Hadoop, backuppc  ). Bring a functional and structured approach to meet compliance rules for public companies and to ensure reliability and robustness.

 

Develop open source projects. Because we are working at the forefront of technology, we are dealing with problems that few have faced. We’re big users of open source, and we’d like to give back to the community.</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;About Criteo [CTRO]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Criteo delivers personalized performance marketing at an extensive scale. Measuring return on post-click sales, Criteo makes ROI transparent and easy to measure. Criteo has over 1,600 employees in 27 offices across the Americas, Europe and Asia-Pacific, serves over 8,500 advertisers worldwide and maintains direct relationships with over 11,000 publishers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our R&amp;amp;D team of close to 300 engineers is building the next generation digital advertising technologies that allow us to manage billions of ad impressions every day. We're working in a very fast-paced release cycle and are adding new capabilities weekly and even daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few figures:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 15 datacenters (8 with computing capacity + 7 dedicated to network connectivity) across US, EU, APAC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• More than 15K servers, running a mix of Linux and Windows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• One of the largest Hadoop clusters in Europe with close to 40PB of storage and 30.000 cores –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 30B HTTP requests and close to 3B unique banners displayed per day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Close to 1M HTTP requests per second handled during peak times&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 40Gbps of bandwidth, half of it through peering exchanges&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recognize that engineering culture is key for building a world-class engineering&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;organization. Our core values are getting stuff done, collaboration and respect, code quality, striving for excellence, and having fun at what we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, please visit http://www.criteolabs.com&lt;/p&gt;</content><company>Criteo</company><address></address><contact>Vincent Landrieux</contact><location></location><phone></phone><link href="http://hire.jobvite.com/CompanyJobs/Careers.aspx?k=Job&amp;c=qRZ9VfwE&amp;j=oS1OZfwq" rel="via"></link></entry>