<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<entry><title>Python core developer</title><link href="https://www.afpy.org/jobs/python-core-developer" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-27T11:23:20+01:00</published><updated>2017-01-27T11:23:21+01:00</updated><author><name>jbaviat</name><email>jb@sqreen.io</email></author><id>https://www.afpy.org/jobs/python-core-developer</id><summary type="html">Position Summary

Candidate will contribute to the development of our existing Python Sqreen Agent. Our agents are running into our customers applications. Candidate will face complex technical challenges to keep a minimal impact on performance.

Candidate will be responsible for designing and developing key Sqreen features for client-side security components, as well as backend infrastructure, leveraging deep expertize in the field of software instrumentation and advanced debugging.

This blog post is a technical, high level overview of our Python agent.

Code will reach production fast using modern development methods and tools. Sqreen platform brings cutting edge technologies to solve complex issues in the simplest form. Candidate will have a high consideration of reliability, low-latency, redundancy, and security.

Our engineers have deep impacts on our products and contribute to protecting millions of products. The candidate will be a key contributor of the engineering team at Sqreen, delivering the best solutions to protect applications.
Discover what you will be working on

These articles from our blog will show you some of the things we are working on, and what our product looks like:

    Behind the Scenes: Building a Dynamic Instrumentation Agent for Python
    Monitor your application security in New Relic Insights
    Embedding JavaScript into Python
    Freeze your Python with str.encode and threads

Give a try now at Sqreen, it's free and the install takes 30 seconds!

Check out some screenshots of the Sqreen dashboard.
</summary><content type="html"></content><company>Sqreen</company><address>23 rue de Cléry
75002 Paris</address><contact>Jean-Baptiste Aviat (CTO)</contact><location></location><phone></phone><link href="https://www.sqreen.io/" rel="about"></link><link href="https://www.sqreen.io/jobs/software-engineer-developer-python.html" rel="via"></link></entry>