<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<entry><title>Web Developer (position available now)</title><link href="https://www.afpy.org/jobs/roygbiv-web_developer" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-06-14T11:01:04+02:00</published><updated>2013-03-31T22:50:21+02:00</updated><author><name>admin</name><email>roy@buzzcar.com</email></author><id>https://www.afpy.org/jobs/roygbiv-web_developer</id><summary type="html">We are a international Funded startup looking for a developer familiar With MVC frameworks to join our team working on web and mobile application development. We build cutting edge Systems with open source technology.</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are using Python/Django and are developing mobile apps for iPhone and Android.  We would like to add to our small team of developers.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Fluency in object oriented language Such as Python, Java, Ruby 
&lt;br /&gt;Experiences with client side technologies, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, etc.. 
&lt;br /&gt;A good understanding of web services and RESTful, Ideally, experience of developing / Extending a REST API. 
&lt;br /&gt;Experience of, or interest in a year, mobile apps 
&lt;br /&gt;Experience of, or interest in a year, working on high-availability and Highly scalable systems. 
&lt;br /&gt;Experience of test-driven development, or at a minimum &amp;quot;significant use of unit testing. 
&lt;br /&gt;Familiarity With Django or RoR 
&lt;br /&gt;Knowledge of relational databases and SQL 
&lt;br /&gt;Experience of, or interest in a year, and Working with Tuning PostgreSQL, &amp;quot;as well as Apache and Nginx. 
&lt;br /&gt;Experience of Working with source control systems like Subversion or Git. 
&lt;br /&gt;Experiences with writing unit tests and CI systems like Hudson. 
&lt;br /&gt;Experience of, or interest in, new gold Emerging Such platforms have iOS, Android, Windows 7 Phone are Highly advantageous 
&lt;br /&gt;Computer Science or related degree&lt;/p&gt;</content><company>Buzzcar</company><address>Buzzcar
86 rue du Faubourg Saint-Denis
75010 Paris</address><contact>Roy Russell</contact><location></location><phone>06 21 87 43 90</phone><link href="http://www.buzzcar.com" rel="about"></link></entry>