<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<entry><title>Vice President of Engineering </title><link href="https://www.afpy.org/jobs/vice-president-of-engineering" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-04T14:47:56+02:00</published><updated>2015-05-04T14:54:34+02:00</updated><author><name>kpler</name><email>lpohl@kpler.com</email></author><id>https://www.afpy.org/jobs/vice-president-of-engineering</id><summary type="html">Who are we ?

Kpler creates SaaS solutions dedicated to energy markets. We developed an innovative technology that aggregates and computes real-time data from multiple sources (logistics, commercial, government and maritime). Our clients are international groups active in the trading of raw materials in the field of energy. Their offices are based all over the world, ranging from Houston to Tokyo.

Smart people make smart products : Our team consists mainly of international profiles that are engineers, sales and analysts.

Who are we looking for ?

We are looking for a motivated and highly skilled VP of Engineering who is ready to take up several challenges and to support our exponential  growth in delivering value to our users. 

What is the job ? 

With a close collaboration with the CTO, you will be in charge of IT development team and be looking after Kpler’s products as a technical expert. The work will include : 

Setting up technical processes and directions to ensure the right evolution of the systems architecture 
Implementation of management methods (daily management of the several projects)
Personally contribute to the development of our platform app.kpler.com (code, test, deployment, support)
Collaborate with members of the sales and support team to deliver new features (based on product road map) in timely and efficient manner, following the users feedback and market needs


As a VP of Engineering, you will have a role of a technical specialist and advisor for the IT team. In this context, you will co-develop and sustain a technical road map with the CTO.

The development team works together towards a common goal to improve our SaaS applications and API.
Our technologies are designed around: Scraper Python&gt;Postgresql&gt;ElasticSearch&gt;Play2 Scala&gt;AngularJS hosted on Heroku &amp; AWS.

You could be the perfect fit if... 

… you hold an engineering degree with at least 10 years experience , of which at least 5 years with managerial functions and ideally with a first experience in start up.

… you have strong  leadership skills as well as an ability to unite teams and manage complex technical projects.

… you have already taken part in data processing projects ( ETL) and / or Python.

… you are fluent in English. 

Top reasons to join the team :

We are a start-up with a very strong growth, with very rare assets (strong profitability, international scope and careers development). We are opening an additional office in Singapore.
Our team is a mix of cultures, backgrounds and experiences which goes in line with our international client base and a global energy products that are traded across the world.
Our office is in the heart of Paris (4eme arrondissement - Beaubourg). 
We offer an attractive remuneration according to candidate’s profile and professional experience (70 - 120 K€).

How to apply ?

Thank you for sending your resume and a short cover letter to Laurine Pohl at jobs@kpler.com.
This permanent position can begin as soon as possible. In the meantime, don’t hesitate to visit our website : www.kpler.com
</summary><content type="html"></content><company>Kpler</company><address>4 rue de jarente</address><contact>Laurine Pohl</contact><location></location><phone>0183818790</phone><link href="http://www.kpler.com" rel="about"></link></entry>