<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<entry><title>Web Designer/Integrator</title><link href="https://www.afpy.org/jobs/web-designer" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-03-18T14:29:47+01:00</published><updated>2014-05-27T10:22:14+02:00</updated><author><name>hropenerp</name><email>jobs@odoo.com</email></author><id>https://www.afpy.org/jobs/web-designer</id><summary type="html">- Design of Web screens for Odoo (Website, event sites, landing pages, etc...)
- Client support for custom Website implementations
- Design of newsletters</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2 class="oe_slogan"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Marketing Department and Professional Services&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 class="oe_slogan"&gt;Company&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Odoo SA is a leading Open Source Business Applications editor. Odoo strategy is based on a unique ecosystem which combines the resources of the community, of its partner’s network and of the editor. The software with more than a thousand downloads a day is one of the most frequently installed business suite worldwide. The company is reinforcing significantly its marketing team. If you enjoy a truly entrepreneurial experience where each person can really make the difference, you should definitely apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class="oe_slogan"&gt;Job Description&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design of Web screens for Odoo (Website, event sites, landing pages, etc...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client support for custom Website implementations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design of newsletters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 class="oe_slogan"&gt;Skills&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bachelor/Master degree in Communication and/or Graphism with no more than 10 years relevant experience. We welcome candidates with no or less work experience provided they demonstrated significant experience through their own projects or initiatives (portfolio).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding of Web Designing is a must.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fluent in English is mandatory. An extra European language is an advantage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTML/CSS knowledge. Javascript and Ajax are a plus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge of Photoshop/Illustrator or equivalent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detail-oriented and highly organized with the ability to handle multiple-tasks simultaneously and meet deadlines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-motivated with a high level of initiative and a sense of urgency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong attention to detail and ability to manage multiple tasks simultaneously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passion, passion, passion for delivering results and driving internal and external customer success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sense of building great, easy to use yet attractive user experiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazingly creative and adaptative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marketing knowledge/sense a plus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 class="oe_slogan"&gt;Why work for Odoo&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Odoo is a fast growing company (we grew from 1 to 85 employees in four years) and has ambitious plans ahead. Each employee has a chance to see the impact of his work and make a real contribution to the success of the company. We foster as open and informal work atmosphere where the quality of what we deliver to the customer is what counts most. With offices in Asia and in the United States, with a network of partners in 26 countries, Odoo combines the reach of a large company and the flexibility of small enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class="oe_slogan"&gt;Interested  ?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apply on &lt;a href="mailto:jobs@openerp.com"&gt;jobs+wd@odoo.com&lt;/a&gt; (Attn : Julien Haeck) and send us your CV and examples of your past work (portfolio). No need for a motivation letter !&lt;/p&gt;</content><company>Odoo SA</company><address>Chaussée de Namur, 40, 1367 Grand-Rosière</address><contact>Julien Haeck</contact><location></location><phone></phone><link href="https://www.odoo.com/" rel="about"></link><link href="https://www.odoo.com/jobs/detail/Web-DesignerIntegrator-47" rel="via"></link></entry>